Which is the health insurance plan that can be
taken even after pregnancy and
covers the delivery expenses after just 3 months?  So the answer is Aditya Birla
Active One Maternity Plan.  Many people
buy this plan as soon as they hear this line.
But this is only half the truth.  Do you
know how much maternity claim will be available in this plan
?  Do you know if there are
any hidden terms and conditions in this plan?
And the most important thing is whether the premium is so high
that you actually get some benefit from taking this plan.
In today's video, we will review Aditya
Birla Active One Maternity Plan in an unbiased
manner.  Every feature and every
condition will be presented to you transparently
so that you do not buy this plan just by hearing the punch line
but you
know the whole truth.  Do watch the video till the end
because this video will not only
save you thousands of rupees but will also make you a smart
pole holder.  So let's
start the video.  To avail Aditya Birla Active On
Maternity Plan, the
entry age of adults should be between 18 years to 45 years.  Only then can
they take this policy.
Both individual and family floater
options are available.  That is, if the
entire family can use a common sum insured, then
you can take the floater option and if you
want separate sum insured for each family member, then
you can also choose the individual option.
You can renew this plan for life long.
But you can claim maternity only once in the entire policy
lifetime.
We will discuss the rest of the maternity features further in the video.
If we talk about sum
insured, then minimum sum insured is ₹1 lakh
till maximum sum insured is ₹2 crore. There are
flexible options
from which you can choose your sum insured.
When any policy holder is
admitted to a hospital for treatment, the
most critical and important choice is that of
room rent, i.e. which room your policy
allows for treatment.  So there is no
limit on room rent under this policy.
Listed day care treatments are also
covered.  That is, those treatments for which 24-
hour admission is not necessary.   If the
surgical procedures are done within three to four hours, then
this plan will also cover that.
If we talk about pre and post
hospitalization expenses.
Expenses related to treatment that were
incurred a few days before admission and continue for a few days after.
So pre-hospitalization expenses
are covered for 90 days and post-
hospitalization expenses will be covered for 180 days.  The
condition is that this treatment
claim is approved by your company.
You get Super Reload Restoration Benefit under Aditya Birla Active On Maternity Plan.
That means up to 100% of the sum insured will be
restored unlimited times, whenever your money is used for treatment.  Apart from this, if
treatment is taken at home on one's own wish i.e. home
care treatment or due to some compulsion
like bed is not available in the hospital
or the patient's condition is very bad and he
cannot go to the hospital, then both these
treatments can be taken under this policy.
But approval of the insurance company
is necessary.  There
is no supplement or capping on ambulance expenses either.  If an
ambulance is used in an emergency situation,
it can also be
claimed under this policy.  Apart from this,
this plan will also cover alternative treatments like AYUSH i.e. Ayurveda, Yoga and Naturopathy, Unani, Siddha and Homeopathy which are becoming quite popular these days.
Organ donor expenses are also
covered in this plan.  If a policy
holder needs to undergo an organ transplant,
that will also be covered up to the
sum insured.  Now comes the most special feature of this plan
, the unique feature is health
returns.  Now who would not want to get
complete coverage but
not have to pay for it.  So you
can do this in this plan because in this you get
health returns.  The
more active you keep your lifestyle, the more you achieve the target of daily number of step
counts, then
you get a monthly target and an
annual target.  So
you keep your step count up with these number of target days.  If you
achieve that target,
you can save up to 100% of the renewal premium.
Because you get health
returns.  These are the reward points
that you can redeem at the time of renewal
and the maximum limit is 100% of
your renewal premium.  This means that
you may not have to pay even ₹1 at the time of renewal.
Now let's talk about some important add-ons.  So the
first add on is Claim Protect.  Claim
Protect gives you coverage for consumables.
Provides coverage for non-medical items.
And it covers all four of Ener One's list
items.  Which
limits the deductions in your health insurance claims.
Apart from this,
you also get the add-on of Super Credit which is a multiple times
cumulative bonus.  Every year when you
renew your policy,
you will get extra super credit equal to 100% of the sum insured
up to a maximum of five
times up to 500%.  And there is no condition as to whether
any claim comes in the entire year or not.
This can be up to five times the maximum sum insured.  But
you will have to take the add on super credit.  Durable
Equipment Cover: These are the equipment that the
doctor recommends
we use after treatment, during recovery.
Like there is a wheelchair, a prosthetic device
, an oxygen concentrator.  So
we can claim these also in the policy.  But
this add-on will have to be taken as durable medical
equipment cover.  Apart from this, you can also reduce the waiting period of your PED
i.e. Pre-Existing Disease
from 3 years to 2 years or 1 year
through this add-on which is named
Reduction in PED Waiting Period and the
final add-on is Annual Health Checkup.
You can get some tests done free of cost throughout the year
but this is
not a part of the standard plan. If you want
such tests to be included in your plan then
you can avail this feature through add-on.  Now
friends, till here we have understood the
basic standard features and
add-ons of Aditya Birla Active One Plan because it is
not necessary that only maternity claim will come.
You may also face some other medical complications before or after that.
So it
is very important that the coverage of the plan is good.
Before I tell you the detailed maternity coverage in this plan.  Let us
also know the waiting periods once.   The
initial waiting period is 30 days.  This means that
only accidental treatment can be taken within the first 30 days of purchasing the policy.
You cannot file any claim for fever, sickness or illness.  Second waiting
period is specific disease.  This
is a slow growing illness.  There are chronic
diseases which will be covered after 24 months.
For this complete list, you
can refer to the policy warnings document.  And the third beating period comes
PED Pre Existing Disease.
Before taking the policy, if the policy holder has any problem
, any medicines he is taking, any treatment he is
undergoing, then we have to tell the insurance company about it.
And by doing so
they can be covered after 3 years of purchasing the policy.
And the final waiting period is the
maternity waiting period that is of 3
months.  Delivery expenses can be claimed only after 3 months.
Now
many people say that Sir, the
waiting period of 3 months will be for pregnancy.
Pregnancy lasts for 9 months.   That
means the overall waiting period becomes 12
months.  but it's not like that.
This policy can be purchased even if the mother
is already pregnant and the
delivery charges can be claimed after 3 months of purchasing the policy.
Let us know the
terms and conditions of maternity and other
coverage.  The first condition is that the
female mother for whom we are
taking maternity coverage should be
above 18 years of age.  Because it is obvious that
they will be able to avail this coverage only after adulthood.  Now
how much is the maternity benefit?  One delivery or
one medical termination of pregnancy can be
covered in a lifetime.  That means
you get coverage for one delivery.  After that you will
never be able to avail delivery coverage again under this plan.
But
how much is this amount?  So here you get a one-time lump sum
benefit of ₹50,000.  Suppose the
policy holder claims delivery expenses
and the cost comes to
₹25,30,000, even then the company will
give him ₹50,000 once and even if the total cost of delivery
comes to ₹1 lakh, the company will still
give him ₹50,000 one time.  That means this is a lump sum
benefit.  It does not depend on your expenses.
When you make a maternity claim, the
company will
give you ₹00 once in your lifetime against maternity.   The
next condition is that to
claim maternity in this policy, it is
necessary for both the parents to be covered in the policy.
Because many people say that if only the mother
buys this policy, can pregnancy be
covered?  It's not like that.  It
is necessary for both parents to be covered under this policy.
And now comes the biggest condition that
you cannot take this one year policy.
You will have to take a long term policy for three years at a time.  Only then can
you avail the benefit of maternity coverage.
Now this question
must be coming to your mind that if it is a 3 year policy and there is
maternity coverage then the policy will become very
expensive.  So we will
see that in the pricing section.  But
before that, let's discuss some more maternity coverage.  Is there
coverage for new born baby in this plan from the time of
birth till 90 days of age
till the child can be added to the policy
and any complication occurs.
What will this policy cover?  There
is no separate coverage for new born baby.  50000
is the lumpsum benefit.  This includes your delivery
charges, new born baby coverage,
vaccination etc. You can use this money for any treatment.  The
company will give you
one time lump sum benefit.  Are
pre and post natal expenses covered in this plan
?  This means that pre-delivery
ultrasounds, sonograms or
post-delivery consultations are not covered.
₹00 will be given once in a lifetime when
you file a claim for delivery.
You can use this money for any service.
But the company does
not provide you this coverage separately.  Now friends, the
matter comes to pricing, for
how much rupees will we get this plan?  Because
many plans offer maternity coverage
but they are very expensive.
So what is the pricing of this plan?  Let us
know.  To understand the pricing,
we have taken a sample family size of two
adults.  Husband's age is 30 years
and wife's age is 28 years.  His address is in
Delhi.  We have chosen sum insured
of ₹1 lakh.
I have added two extra add-ons to this plan to enhance the coverage.
First is Super Credit which
increases the sum insured up to five times.
Because such features are available in all other plans also.
And the second is
Claim Protect which will
also add consumable items to this plan so that there is a
very low deduction on each claim.  So this
family gets ₹1 lakh coverage with maternity coverage for
3 years at ₹68,200.   Is
it expensive?  Out of this, ₹25,000 is
only for maternity.  That means if a
policy holder takes a maternity claim,
he gets ₹50,000, while for just
₹18,200
he gets 3 years of health insurance
coverage and the features of the plan that
we have seen are also no less because
it is a combo.  The base plan is Aditya
Birla Active One and it also
comes with an add-on called Health Booster, whose maternity
cover has been added to this plan.
So the name of the plan becomes Aditya Birla
Active One Maternity Plan and you know
how popular the Active One plan is.  Its
variants Next Vital Max Max Plus
are already very popular.  Now
we know all the features, benefits, add-ons, pricing, waiting period and maternity coverage.
What is my opinion about this plan?  What is my opinion?
I will tell you that also.  First of all let us
discuss what are the good things
?  The first good point is that
pregnant women can also take this policy.
There is no waiting period of two to three years. The
plan can be taken even after pregnancy, considering maternity
coverage.  The second benefit is very low waiting
period.  In many health insurance plans,
you will get a waiting period of 3 years
or 2 years.  If you reduce it, the maternity
premium itself becomes more than the base plan.
So here
you are given a standard coverage within a very reasonable premium.
Third benefit I would say because
Aditya Birla Active One is its base plan.
So the standard features are also very good.
Because once we have paid the money and
taken the policy, we can file any claim against it.
We may have to seek treatment for any medical condition.  So it becomes
very important that the
plan other than maternity should also be very good.
And this plan has all the features
that are offered in a latest plan today.
And the final benefit that
I observe is the reasonable premium.  This means that
if the maternity benefit is
availed, you get a good amount of coverage in this premium.
And apart from this,
you already have health returns.  If you
maintain an active lifestyle,
you may get even more discount at the time of renewal.
But this was just
one side of the coin.  There are some drawbacks in this plan
which I noticed.  The first
drawback is the fixed maternity coverage
of ₹50,000 which is not sufficient for every individual and
every city to cope with the medical inflation.
If you live
in small towns in 12 to 3 cities, then
this plan
gives you good coverage at a very reasonable premium.
But if you live in a big city or
metro city, then you will
not get much benefit from taking this plan
because the lump sum benefit is of ₹50,000 and
if the maternity cost is much more than this then
its use reduces there.
Now when the sum insured for maternity itself is falling short,
apart from that, coverage for the new born baby is also
not included in it.  When any
delivery takes place, the newborn baby is at great
risk.  There is a lot of risk to the new born baby.
Complications related to it are
not covered under maternity benefits.  So
a large section is still at risk.
However, after 90 days we
can add this child.  But at that time the immunity
already becomes a little better.
Coverage for initial complications will have to be
taken from this ₹00 only.  And the final
drawback that I see is coverage of a single
delivery in a lifetime.
Only one delivery will be covered in the entire lifetime.  If you
want more coverage than that, this
plan does not offer it.  If you
like this plan then the next question that will
come to your mind is where can you get this plan?
So this is neither on the insurance company's website
nor with the agent.  You will only
find this on Policyba's website.  You can go there and
get it.  A disclaimer this is
not a paid or promotional video.  If you
like the plan and compare it, then you
can go and get it.  My job is to
tell you transparently what the plan is,
how much money you will pay for it and where you
can get it from.
How do you like this maternity plan?
What did you like and what did you dislike about this plan?  You
can also tell me your opinion in the comment section.
And apart from this plan, if you want
me to compare three or four more maternity plans
so that I can show you better options, then
tell me that too in the comment section.
I will make a separate dedicated video for you.
If you liked the video and the information given in the video, then
you can like the video to show your love and support.
And do
n't forget to subscribe to the channel for such unbiased transparent information videos.
However, choosing a maternity plan can be quite
confusing.  We may
miss out on many benefits and
may also choose the wrong policy.  So
what things should we keep in mind while choosing a maternity plan?
This video will hold your hand throughout the process,
please watch it.  I, Harvinder Singh, now
take your permission.  I will meet you
in the next video.  Till then take care, stay fit
and stay healthy.  Jai Hind.